Guide to the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union Local 9 Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, Local 9 records
1935-1990
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5809
International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union.$bLocal 9
13.04 cubic feet 14 boxes
Records relating to the ILWU-Local 9
International Longshore and Warehouse Union, Local 9 is a local union that represents port workers at Seattle-Tacoma International aiport. A part of their jurisdiction was formerly Port of Seattle warehouses, but by the late 2000s, those contracts were no longer in place.
Minutes, corrspondence, subject files, financial records, picket signs, and voting box from local union elections.
Open to all users, but access to portions of the papers restricted. Contact Special Collections for details.
International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union.$bLocal 9$vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington)
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions
- International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, Local 9 records, 1935-1990; 5809-001; 13.04 cubic feet 14 boxes
  Minutes, corrspondence, subject files, financial records, picket signs, and voting box from local union elections.
  Open to all users, but access to portions of the papers restricted. Contact Special Collections for details.
  Mike Pavelic, Secretary Treasurer of International Longshore and Warehouse Union, Local 9, 2013
  - Series I: Subject Files on Employer, 1936-1983 (Box 1-4)
    - Case files and Office Files, Including Seattle Labor Unity Council, 1936, 1960-1977, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Case Files and Miscellaneous Agreements, 1948-1983 (Box 2)
    - Contracts, 1950-1990 (Box 3)
    - Port of Seattle, Mixed Divisions, 1966-1981 (Box 4)
  - Series II: Local Operations, 1935-1970s (Box 5-11)
    - General Local Office Files, 1960-1980 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous Office Files, 1970s (Box 6)
    - General Office Files, including constitutions, meeting minutes, etc., 1960-1990 (Box 7)
    - Receipts, Minutes, Ledgers, 1935-1947 (Box 8)
    - Receipts, Minutes, Ledgers, 1935-1947 (Box 9)
    - Receipts, Minutes, Ledgers, 1935-1947 (Box 10)
    - Financials, Executive Board Minutes, Membership Minutes, etc., 1937-1969 (Box 11)
  - Series III: Artifacts, Photographs, and Ephemera, Undated (Box 12-14)
    - Ballot Box, Undated (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Photographs of ILWU Local 9 Strikes, WTO Protests, Marches and ILWU President Jimmy Herman, Undated (Box 13)
    - ILWU Local 9 Strike Signs, Undated (Box 14)